The question is, how do we pass data down to our components?
So this is where we talk about the idea and it's called props,
which is shorthand for properties.
The reason why I like the concept of props a lot is because if you think about it,
they're really just data attributes on your HTML element.
But it sounds really fancy when you say props,
but really it's just you're passing an attribute a value,
and then that component can access that attribute.
That's really what it is.
So I think of props as custom attributes.
Well, what do we need? We need the character list.
So for now, I'm going to add a prop called characters,
and this is going to be passing down our character list.
So then I can go ahead and bind it to character list like this.
Then does anyone know what I'm missing here?
colon, yep, because I need to v-bind this to make it dynamic.
So I'm going to just do the shorthand for colon.
But that's not good enough though,
because after all, what we just did was we just passed it in data.
But one of the things I really like about view,
when it comes, it's not view specific,
but I did like this when I started learning about it,
is that it's really all about trying to document your components
and making it easier for people to use.
So inside of your options, you have the ability
to define what props you're going to get, right?
So actually, before I do the object one,
the simplest way to define your props
is through an array of strings.
So I could just be like characters like that.
And then you can see here, let me save that, okay?
What this means now is that if I do this.characters,
view will know this character's reference
refers to this prop up here.
And so if I save this now and refresh,
you'll notice our statistics suddenly works again.
Now the thing is though, I only show you this
because in case you see this in the wild,
this is code smell, because again, characters as a string
doesn't tell you very much about what you expect as a prop.
If you're interested in enterprise level patterns
and that kind of stuff,
be sure to check out the production grade view
that I recorded before.
And so that covers a lot of the different patterns
that you'll see in enterprise apps.
And so this is kind of like a snippet
of something that I mentioned.
Okay, so when it comes to props,
I recommend defining it via object.
Why?
Because what we can do is for characters,
we can do things like define what kind of type
that we're expecting.
And again, this is not type and typescript perspective.
This is more of a runtime check,
like view helps you out when you pass something funny down.
It'll just kind of highlight like,
hey, you told me you wanted this.
Why is it something different?
So in this case, I know it's just gonna be an array.
More importantly, I can say this is a required property.
Or I could say, I could also define
a default property on it as well.
But for this particular case,
all we need to worry about is the fact that
it's a required property, and that's important
because what you're doing here
is basically self-documenting the component
so that people in the future can actually use it correctly.
And so when I save this here,
you see that we're refreshed, this is good.
But then when we go back to app.view,
let's say I accidentally tried to use
Bender statistics without passing the component.
Let's see if we'll let you yell at me.
Bum bum bum bum bum.
So this time it doesn't yell at me.
But there are times where I think,
actually let me do this real quick.
If I do characters equals one, two, three.
Save.
Looks like it's not doing any checks for me at the moment.
It's being kind of finicky.
But anyhow, at the bare minimum,
when you're doing this, you can actually see
it's easy to read, easy to understand,
and then more importantly,
makes your app easier to maintain.
So once again, we are a character list like this.
Oops.
Okay.
And so props really is basically the glue
to which we can connect our parent components
into our child components.
There's a question though?
Functions as props.
Okay.
So this is a hotly-divated one.
So the question here is around the concept
of functions as props.
So in other words, to set up the example here,
let me go into the sandbox one instead, just to show.
Okay.
So let's say in base counter, we had a props.
And this is actually something that I think
is more common in React code bases.
So in app.view, we saw that we actually
actually scoped the increment counter
directly to the component, right?
Well, theoretically, what you could do
is with this concept is that you would have
your methods at your parent component.
So it'd be at this level, right?
And you'd have this increment function.
And then what you pass down to the component
is the actual increment function.
So it would look something like this, right?
And then in terms of how this would be,
how it would look from a component perspective,
you would have this increment prop,
and it's like type function, right?
And then just be like, oops, required true.
There's an example of a props.
Personally, I am not a fan of passing functions down
as props.
The reason for this is because I know that,
especially when we are programming,
we get caught up in trying to do factory functions
and with factory components,
where it becomes very easy to genericize everything.
And so that's why I think one of the reasons
it even got popular to pass functions down
is because you're basically saying,
as a parent, I'm gonna tell the child what to run.
But what I found with that a lot of times
is that now you're starting to kind of conflate the,
like I feel like the parent starts to do too much work
in terms of like, if the scope of the child
is meant to increment,
I found very few times where it didn't make sense
for the child to own that from the beginning,
as far as like functionality-wise.
So in this example, I tend to think about this
in the add new airbender form.
Like the parent app owns the list of airbenders,
and the form has the what is a new airbender
and how do I modify it.
But then when I wanna actually add that to that list,
like I could modify the list in the child,
but that feels dirtier than having the parent
own that function that actually adds it to the list.
I love this question.
So that is actually a good lead-in after the exercise.
I'll call it what I consider the more standard pattern
of dealing with that.
And so to recap, in case anyone couldn't hear,
is that let's go back to the example brought up
was inside of my avatar airbender component.
Earlier, you might have heard me say, for example,
that the component hit a limit, and there's a reason for that.
But for the favorite character list, as was mentioned,
if we were to break out favorite character right here
into its own component, it's tricky because at this point,
favorite list is also dependent on like,
there's like the data exists in the parent.
And so you don't necessarily wanna pass the data
into the child for the child to modify.
But at the same time, then it sounds like it would be better
to then pass a function to the child
to tell it what to do, right?
But I'll leave that a little bit on the cliffhanger,
but just know that there is a better way
than passing functions down as props
when it comes to that scenario.